<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>CSSE News Articles</title><link>https://www.monmouth.edu/department-of-csse/news-events/</link><description>All news articles and urls from the Monmouth University computer science and software engineering department news archive.</description><lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2020 19:00:05 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>PyRSS2Gen-1.1.0</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>SE Graduate Named to Forbes List of 30 Under 30</title><link>https://www.monmouth.edu/department-of-csse/news-events/#skhalifah2</link><description>Saoud Khalifah (BSSE 2013, MSSE 2014) was recently included in Forbes Magazines List of 30 Under 30 for his work to start and develop Fakespot, a site and service that uses artificial intelligence techniques such as natural language processing to detect fraudulent or biased product reviews. Fakespot has been used by millions to analyze product reviews on sites such as Amazon, Best Buy, Walmart and Yelp. Read more in magazine </description></item><item><title>CSSE Students Finish First and Second in MU TechPitch Competition</title><link>https://www.monmouth.edu/department-of-csse/news-events/#techpitch2019</link><description>Senior CS majors Patricia Skora and Victoria Johnson, representing their company CheckMate, won first place in MU’s November TechPitch competition. They developed and presented a sailing competition verification app, VERISail, which would help inspectors at sailing events ensure that competing sailboats are class approved. VERISail would work with manufacturers of sailboat components to include QR codes and holograms that inspectors could quickly scan to verify compliance at competitions, easing a previously tedious and error-prone ...</description></item><item><title>Student Commemoration for Dr. Bill Tepfenhart</title><link>https://www.monmouth.edu/department-of-csse/news-events/#btepfenhart</link><description>On April 17, 2019, CSSE students held a Celebration of Impact event for the late Dr. Bill Tepfenhart. Dr. Tepfenhart taught at Monmouth for 20 years and left a positive and lasting impact on many students and fellow faculty. He served in many capacities within the CSSE Department and was also a permanent member of the Honors Council. The event was attended by approximately 50 people including his wife, Mariana and sister, Laura. Many ...</description></item><item><title>2019 High School Programming Competition</title><link>https://www.monmouth.edu/department-of-csse/news-events/#hsprogcontest2019</link><description>The CSSE department and IEEE/ACM Student Chapter hosted the 2019 High School Programming Competition on Friday, March 1, 2019. Twenty two teams of high school students from the Ranney School, East Brunswick, the Toms River School District, Middletown, Red Bank Regional and Monmouth Regional High School competed in this event. Many thanks to our industry sponsors Commvault and iCIMS, as well as Dr. Raman Lakshmanan who provided prizes for the winning teams. View the ...</description></item><item><title>SE Senior Wins Universitys October TECHPitch Event and Competes in NJ TechLaunch BullPen #11</title><link>https://www.monmouth.edu/department-of-csse/news-events/#kreda1</link><description> Software Engineering Senior, Kalyna Reda, and her startup, MedEd, won the October 2018 Monmouth University TECHPitch Event. She then represented Monmouth University in New Jerseys premier investor pitch event, TechLaunch Bullpen #11, on November 14, 2018, competing for investor/entrepreneur support and $20,000 of professional services. The TechLaunch event was held in Pozycki Auditorium. About MedEd: MedEd is a mobile application that will improve the accuracy and quality of paper evaluations that track the ...</description></item><item><title>SE Graduate in Spring 2018 Issue of Monmouth Magazine</title><link>https://www.monmouth.edu/department-of-csse/news-events/#skhalifah1</link><description>Saoud Khalifah (BSSE 2013, MSSE 2014) was featured in the Spring 2018 issue of Monmouth Magazine, in an article titled, Consumer Protector: Tired of getting duped by fake product reviews online? Saoud Khalifah’s website can help you shop smarter. In the article, he recalls how his personal on-line shopping experiences as a student led to his idea to develop Fakespot.com, a website that automatically scans reviews to give consumers better insight about the products ...</description></item><item><title>2018 High School Programming Competition</title><link>https://www.monmouth.edu/department-of-csse/news-events/#hsprogcontest2018</link><description>The CSSE department and IEEE/ACM Student Chapter hosted the 2018 High School Programming Competition on Friday, February 23, 2018. Twenty four teams of high school students from Middletown South, Ocean Township, the Freehold Regional School District, the Toms River School District, Henry Hudson, Red Bank Regional, and Donovan Catholic participated in this event. Industry sponsors IBM, Commvault and Sparta Systems provided prizes for the winning teams, and the Macaluso Group donated computing-related books for ...</description></item><item><title>CS Graduate in Fall 2017 School of Science Graduate Spotlight</title><link>https://www.monmouth.edu/department-of-csse/news-events/#jbuck2017</link><description>Jessica Buck (BSCS 2014) was the featured alumna in the Fall 2017/Winter 2018 School of Science newsletter. She is a current business analyst for MedForce. She also worked previously as a software developer and computer programmer/analyst for other healthcare companies. She recalls her journey from earning an Associates of Arts degree in English at Brookdale to a Bachelors in CS at Monmouth, all while balancing school and motherhood. She also recalls the supportive atmosphere ...</description></item><item><title>CS Graduate in Fall 2017 Issue of Monmouth Magazine</title><link>https://www.monmouth.edu/department-of-csse/news-events/#janastasio1</link><description>Jessica Anastasio (BSCS 2016) was featured in the Fall 2017 issue of Monmouth Magazine, in an article titled, 5 Steps To Landing Your Dream Tech Job: Buzzfeed’s Jessica Anastasio shares her recipe for success. In the article, she recounts the challenges she faced and overcame as a female CS major. She also offers practical advise to help students break into and advance in careers in technology. Read more of the spotlight </description></item><item><title>Department Hosts Random Hacks of Kindness Junior: Kids Coding for A Cause</title><link>https://www.monmouth.edu/department-of-csse/news-events/#rhokjr2017</link><description>The Department of Computer Science and Software Engineering, in conjunction with Random Hacks of Kindness Junior (RHoKJr), hosted its first Random Hacks of Kindness Junior: Kids Coding for A Cause event on October 28, 2017 in the School of Science atrium. Nearly 50 female students in grades four through eight participated in the daylong event. Students were divided into 13 teams, with each team working on behalf of a local nonprofit organization, guided by ...</description></item><item><title>CS Graduate in Summer 2017 Issue of Monmouth Magazine</title><link>https://www.monmouth.edu/department-of-csse/news-events/#licata1</link><description>Giuseppe Licata (BSCS 2017) was featured in the Summer 2017 issue of Monmouth Magazine, in an article titled, Bot Man: Giuseppe Licata is coding his way to the top, one chatbot at a time. He discusses the rising importance of chatbots in online services. The article mentions his contributions as part of the winning team in the February 2017 RightAnswers Chatbot Challenge at MU. Read more in the summer issue </description></item><item><title>CS Graduate in 2017 School of Science Graduate Spotlight</title><link>https://www.monmouth.edu/department-of-csse/news-events/#campos1</link><description>Taylor Campos (BSCS 2017) was featured in a 2017 School of Science Graduate Spotlight. She recounts what factors attracted her to Monmouth University, why MU was a good fit for her and how MU prepared her to be successful. She also discusses her experiences as a IEEE/ACM chapter officer and School of Science Peer Mentor. Read more. about Taylor ..</description></item><item><title>CSSE Students Participate in RightAnswers Customer Service Chatbot Challenge</title><link>https://www.monmouth.edu/department-of-csse/news-events/#rightanswers2017</link><description>CSSE students Mada Almansoor, Phil DiMarco, Darius Jenkins and Giuseppe Licata participated in interdisciplinary teams that were finalists in the RightAnswers Customer Service Chatbot challenge. The chatbot development competition was comprised of Monmouth University business and computer science/software engineering students. Their task was to develop software that delivers automated customer service support through messaging platforms. Read more about the challenge </description></item><item><title>2016 High School Programming Competition</title><link>https://www.monmouth.edu/department-of-csse/news-events/#hsprogcontest2016</link><description>The CSSE department and IEEE/ACM Student Chapter hosted the 2016 High School Programming Competition on Friday March 4, 2016. Twenty teams of 3 students from 10 area high schools participated in this event. Read more about the 2017 competition </description></item><item><title>IEEE/ACM Student Chapter Receives NCWIT Student Seed Fund Gift from Google.org</title><link>https://www.monmouth.edu/department-of-csse/news-events/#googleaward2016</link><description>Monmouth Universitys IEEE/ACM Student Chapter has been awarded a National Center for Women and Information Technology (NCWIT) Student Seed Fund gift of $3,000. This gift, sponsored by Google.org, will be used to create an Association for Computing Machinery Committee on Women in Computing (ACM-W) chapter on campus. Student chapters of ACM-W serve to increase recruitment and retention of women in computing fields at the university level, and will offer students activities and projects that ...</description></item><item><title>Faculty Member and 5 Students Attend 2015 Grace Hopper Celebration of Women in Computing Conference in Houston, TX</title><link>https://www.monmouth.edu/department-of-csse/news-events/#gracehopper2015</link><description>For the second year in a row, Monmouth faculty and students have been part of the world’s largest gathering of women technologists at the Grace Hopper Celebration of Women in Computing Conference. Two students, Taylor Klodowski and Jessica Anastasio, were among the 26% of applicants to receive a GHC Scholarship Grant, providing full support for attendance at the 2015 event. The Computer Science Software Engineering Department and The School of Science provided support for ...</description></item><item><title>Inaugural High School Programming Competition</title><link>https://www.monmouth.edu/department-of-csse/news-events/#hsprogcontest2015</link><description>The Monmouth University IEEE/ACM Student Chapter is hosting their inaugural High School Programming Competition on Thursday May 14, 2015. One 3-person team can be registered per school. $40 registration for the team and advisor includes continental breakfast and lunch. Prizes will be awarded. Contact: Prof. Jamie Kretsch</description></item><item><title>CSSE Faculty and Students Participating in Hour of Code</title><link>https://www.monmouth.edu/department-of-csse/news-events/#hourofcode2014</link><description> Monmouth University’s Computer Science and Software Engineering Department is encouraging everyone to join in on the largest learning event in history: The Hour of Code. Students and faculty from the department will be visiting several area schools to help kick-off their Hour of Code activities, and we have scheduled several Hour of Code sessions on our West Long Branch campus. One Hour of Code session on Wednesday Dec. 10 is for current University ...</description></item><item><title>CSSE Juniors Win Awards At Second Annual Marathon Hackathon</title><link>https://www.monmouth.edu/department-of-csse/news-events/#hackathon0614</link><description>Two CSSE Juniors, Justin Schlemm and Taylor Klodowski recently earned a second-place award at Marathon Data Systems’ second annual “Marathon Hackathon,” which was held June 7 and 8 at Marathon Data Systems’ office in Neptune. They also received a $400 prize for creating a mobile application to connect volunteers to relevant charity events. Their application, ChariTEA (technology, effort, action), allows charities to post times, dates and skill-set requirements when volunteers are needed. Volunteers can ...</description></item><item><title>IEEE/ACM Student Chapter attends IEEE Region 1 Student Conference at NJIT</title><link>https://www.monmouth.edu/department-of-csse/news-events/#ieee0314</link><description>On March 29th, 2014, the IEEE/ACM student chapter of Monmouth University attended the IEEE Region 1 Student Conference at NJIT. At the conference Jake Vernon, President, had the opportunity to speak on behalf of the chapter during the Student Chapter Showcase. Following the showcase was the micro-mouse competition, where Sidhdhesh Patel, James Blessing, Justin Schlemm, Zixi Li, and Jake Vernon were able to display all their hard work that had been put into the ...</description></item><item><title>CS Grad Student Featured in Faces of Monmouth</title><link>https://www.monmouth.edu/department-of-csse/news-events/#delfattore1</link><description>Christopher Del Fattore (BSCS, 2013) has a featured profile in Faces of Monmouth. As part of his Spring 2013 senior project, Chris and his team developed The Mark, a Java application allowing users to comment on PDF documents. The project earned his team the Deans Award of Excellence for Undergraduate Research at MUs Student Research Conference. After earning his bachelors degree in computer science, he landed a job at ForeFront, Inc., a Fair Haven, ...</description></item><item><title>CSSE Department to Offer New Master of Science in Information Systems Degree</title><link>https://www.monmouth.edu/department-of-csse/news-events/#msis</link><description>The Monmouth University Board of Trustees has approved the Department of Computer Science and Software Engineerings proposed Master of Science in Information Systems (MS-IS) degree program. The program is scheduled to be implemented starting in the Fall semester of 2014. The mission of the MS-IS program will be to integrate information technology and business management at the graduate level to provide well-trained students who would enter and be successful in local IT sectors. The ...</description></item><item><title>Two Teams of CS Seniors Receive Deans Award of Excellence in Undergraduate Research</title><link>https://www.monmouth.edu/department-of-csse/news-events/#deansAwardSp13</link><description>The following two teams of CS Seniors have received the School of Science Deans Award of Excellence in Undergraduate Research in integrative research: Steven Cregan, Garrett Haas, Gage Jackson, Patrick McDonald Project Title: Put-A-Tag: A Generic Tagging Tool Faculty Mentor: Dr. Cui Yu Christopher Del Fattore, Bruce Lukens, Jesse Rosero Project Title: The Mark: A Commenting Application Faculty Mentor: Dr. Cui Yu They received the awards at the Universitys Annual Student Research Conference, sponsored ...</description></item><item><title>Team of Current and Former CSSE Dept. Students Wins 24-Hour Hackathon To Benefit Jersey Shore Recovery From Super Storm Sandy</title><link>https://www.monmouth.edu/department-of-csse/news-events/#hackathon0413</link><description>On April 28-29, three of our Monmouth CSSE students participated inand wona 24-hour Hackathon called the Jersey Shore Comeback-A-Thon. Gary Kagan is currently an undergraduate Software Engineering major at Monmouth University, and Cory Cardio received his MS last year. Together with Margaret Kim, also a past CSSE student, they formed Team Mango and worked through the night on Saturday, developing a new and novel mobile app. The theme of the event was Jersey Shore ...</description></item><item><title>Software Engineering Dept. Graduate Reflects On MU Experience</title><link>https://www.monmouth.edu/department-of-csse/news-events/#vDesai</link><description>Software Engineering Dept. graduate (2012) Vishruti Desai wrote a graduation essay that appeared in the Asbury Park Press on January 19, 2013. (Excerpt:) I joined MU in fall 2011 to study MS in software engineering. I am glad that I selected software engineering at MU. I am very much thankful to Dr. Daniela Rosca for providing me guidance on choosing the MS course. The faculty staff of Software Engineering offered me a wide range ...</description></item></channel></rss>